amiando.com 2018-12-06

# Privacy at XING

  1. [Privacy Policy](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy)

  * Last updated: 3 September 2018
  * This Privacy Policy shall apply to the entire service XING and its applications. 
  * XING SE is the body responsible for the processing of personal data.
  * Our Data Protection Officer is Felix Lasse. 

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/general-information)

### 

1\. General statement about the purposes of data processing

The main reason we process personal data is to fulfil our contractual obligations towards our users. The processing of data is required, for example, for us to be able to suggest suitable contacts, services and information to you. 

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/information-about-the-purposes-of-data-processing)

### 

2\. Information you provide to us

This refers to data we obtain from you directly and information you publish and send on XING Websites such as:

  * Login details (e.g. username and password)
  * Profile information (e.g. job title, company name, industry, educational background, contact options, photo)
  * Messages, group posts, event participation, billing details

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/information-you-provide-us-with)

### 

3\. Information we automatically obtain through your use of XING

Data about you is automatically collated by means of tracking while you visit or make use of the XING service. Here you can find out: 

  * How tracking works
  * Why we make use of tracking (ensuring security, provision of our service, measurement and optimisation of advertising, and determination of statistics). 

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/information-we-automatically-receive-through-your-use-of-xing)

### 

4\. Information we obtain about you from other sources

Some information about you that we process does not come directly from you. This might be the case, for example, if a user shares this information with us or we obtain it from other sources. 

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/information-we-receive-about-you-from-other-sources)

### 

5\. Who may receive information about you? 

You can find out here who we disclose data to, what purpose this serves, and how you can customise your privacy settings on XING. By the way, we only ever pass your personal data on to third parties when: 

  * This is required for us to fulfil our business purposes, e.g. when we make your profile accessible to another user
  * You have granted your consent (e.g. for use of an external application)
  * We are obliged to do so on legal grounds, by court order, or at the request of another official authority. 

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/who-may-receive-information-about-you)

You can find detailed information here about your various rights:

  * Your right to object
  * Your right of access
  * Your right to erasure
  * Other rights

[

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/what-rights-can-you-assert) [

Find out more

](https://privacy.xing.com/en/privacy-policy/terms-used-in-our-privacy-policy)

## Privacy on XING in more detail.

Our Privacy Policy is designed to help you quickly locate the information most relevant to you. If you'd prefer to read the conventional long version, please click here.

**Cookies:**

Small files that enable us to store specific information related to you, the user, on your end device. You can edit the settings of your browser to prevent cookies from being saved.

**Third country:**

A country outside of the European Union.

**EU GDPR:**

The Regulation (EU) 2016/679 of the European Parliament and the Council dated 27 April 2016 on the protection of individuals with regard to the processing of personal data, on the free movement of such data, and on the repeal of the EU Data Protection Directive 95/46/EC.

**Newsletter:**

Newsletters or status e-mails and advertising for XING’s own similar products and services, or surveys for the purpose of XING’s own market research.

**Personal data:**

Pursuant to Article 4 (1) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), any information relating to an identified or identifiable natural person; an identifiable natural person is one who can be identified, directly or indirectly, in particular by reference to an identifier such as a name, an identification number, location data, an online identifier or to one or more factors specific to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural or social identity of that natural person.

**Pixel:**

Pixel: An image file or link to an image file that is added to the website code but not sent to your end device (e.g. PC, smartphone, etc.). Pixels are usually used in conjunction with cookies.

**Profile:**

The page on the XING Websites where the personal data made available by the user is displayed in the social network.

**Profiling:**

Pursuant to Article 4 (4) of the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR), any form of automated processing of personal data consisting of the use of personal data to evaluate certain personal aspects relating to a natural person, in particular to analyse or predict aspects concerning that natural person’s performance at work, economic situation, health, personal preferences, interests, reliability, behaviour, location or move-ments.

**Social network:**

The contact and communication forums belonging to the applications of the service XING.

**XING:**

The service XING and the applications belonging to the service XING.

**XING Websites:**

All websites, subdomains, aliases, mobile applications, background applications, web services and embedding in third-party websites where the service XING is available.
